# **Mohammed Abdulsalam**

LinkedIn | GitHub | Codeforces

Email: moha4mach@gmail.com | Mobile: +20 12 1165 0982

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

I am a highly skilled web developer with over 3 year of experience in HTML, CSS, Javascript, 2 year of experience in PHP, MySQL. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as Laravel, React, and Vue.js. I worked on several projects using native PHP and MySQL/MariaDB, and have experience designing REST APIs.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : PHP, SQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, TeX

**Frameworks** : Laravel, React.js

Libraries : PHPUnit, PHP Spread Sheet, ECDSA, React Router, Styled Components, Socket.IO

**Databases** : MySQL, MariaDB, SQLlite

Methodoligies : BEM

**Concepts** : OOP, MVC, Regular Expressions, Accessibility (WCAG), REST, ERD Design, SRS Design

**Dev Tools**: Vim, Visual Studio Code, XDebug, Vite, Git, Github, Apache HTTP Server, Linux, cron, Docker, Insomnia

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Front End Developer Volunteer**

Jan 2023 – Present

Location: Alexandria, Egypt

UCCD KSU

Remote – Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt

- Designed and developed dynamic and responsive student management website using React.js
- Worked with **REST APIs** to retrieve and display data from backend

## **Vice Head of Web Development Committee**

Sep 2022 – Apr 2023

GDSC KSU

Remote – Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt

- Share knowledge and experience with my fellow members
- Make sure the plan is suitable for members
- Demonstrated critical topics in core Front End technologies, including SEO, and Accessibility, through number of sessions

Feb 2022 – Present

Freelance

- Design and development of websites using HTML, CSS, and Javascript
- Desing and development of back-ends using PHP, MYSQL/MariaDB
- · Worked on REST APIs for medium-sized systems
- Analysis of stakeholders reuirements, and design ERD, SRS, and various documents
- Deployed and maintained websites on AWS EC2 linux server

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Kafrelsheikh - Faculty of Computers and Information

Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt Sep 2020 – Jul 2024

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.25/4

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Visualizing Sorting Algorithms**

HTML, CSS, Javascript

Source Code

- Implemented different sorting algorithms in Javascript
- Used Asynchronous Programming using Javascript to visualize sorting
- Deployed on GitHub pages via GitHub Actions

**UCCD** Website

React.js, Git

<u>Demo</u> *Private* 

Demo

Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, CSS, and Javascript

- Utilized responsive design to ensure compatibility across all devices
- Communicated with backend using a **RESTful API**

Bookopia PHP, Laravel, MVC, SCSS

Source Code

A library management system written in PHP / Laravel. Build with MVC architectural pattern

- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, and SCSS
- Utilized Laravel Components to enhance the modularity of the frontend
- Extended **Blade** funcionality by writing customized **Directives**, that help us write less code

**Salem Clinic Website** 

PHP, MySQL, Javascript, Git

Private

- Designed and developed dynamic monolith website using PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- · Worked on admin panel providing article management, content management, and admins priviliges
- Developed Markup to HTML library using PHP, and Javascript, utilized in articles creation, editing, and viewing
- Deployed using Apache server on AWS EC2 instance, with domain name and HTTPS certificate configured
- Used a cronjob to backup data periodically

Simple API Framework PHP Source Code

- Developed various utilities to facilitate RESTful APIs developing
- Implemented my own Router, and JWT utilities

## **Clinic Management System (ERP)**

PHP, MariaDB, Socket.IO

Private

- A CRUD application exposed using a RESTful API made with PHP
- Analysed stakeholders requirements, deigned ERD based on this analysis
- Used XDebug to facilitate debugging process, and PHPUnit to automate unit testing
- Worked on many features that support bussiness logic, includes live queues, activity log, authorization rules and priviliges, payroll system, patient management system, etc...
- Used Socket.IO under Node.js to build socket server to maintain live queues data between clients

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

• ITI - Web Development Using PHP (150 hrs.)